<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writeups on Fl1x&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://fl1xh.github.io/tags/writeups/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writeups on Fl1x&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 19:25:46 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fl1xh.github.io/tags/writeups/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[CyberDefenders] Ulysses Writeup</title>
      <link>https://fl1xh.github.io/posts/wu_cbd_ulysses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 19:25:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fl1xh.github.io/posts/wu_cbd_ulysses/</guid>
      <description>Background Question 1 Question 2 Question 3 Question 4 Question 5 Question 6 Question 7 Question 8 Question 9 Question 10 Question 11 Background A Linux server was possibly compromised and a forensic analysis is required in order to understand what really happened. Hard disk dumps and memory snapshots of the machine are provided in order to solve the challenge (https://cyberdefenders.org/blueteam-ctf-challenges/41).
Challenge Files:
victoria-v8.kcore.img: memory dump done by dd’ing /proc/kcore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[BTLO] Malicious PowerShell Analysis Writeup</title>
      <link>https://fl1xh.github.io/posts/wu_btlo_malicious_powershell_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 12:07:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fl1xh.github.io/posts/wu_btlo_malicious_powershell_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Question 1 Question 2 Question 3 Question 4 Question 5 Question 6 Conclusion Introduction As its name suggests, this challenge will allow us to analyze a malicious powershell file.
CyberChef is often a useful tool for this sort of analysis and we’re gonna use it.
After downloading the .zip archive, we get a file called &amp;quot;ps_script.txt&amp;quot;.
Here we get the content with a simple cat command. POwersheLL -w hidden means that a hidden PowerShell window (invisible to the user) is opened, and -ENCOD, shorthand for encoded shows that the script was encoded with Base64.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
